[Music]
you can Define production bill of
material or routing on the stock keeping
unit this can be useful if a stock
keeping unit represents a different
variant of product and it needs to use a
different component or maybe it
represents different location where some
production equipment is not available or
it is different so you need to use a
different routing to produce uh this
Goods this build definitely impact the
cost so the standard cost for items
produced for specific variant or
specific location will be carefully
copied from the stock keeping unit let's
see the Demo First activate the standard
cost per stock keeping unit in a
manufacturing setup then navigate to
stock keeping unit card for the
reservoir assembly on the main location
at this location we will use
subcontracting routing in instead of
internal capacity let's use new function
to calculate production standard cost
now stock keeping unit has a different
cost than an item card and next steps we
will examine the impact we have the
release production order which contains
two lines although the item Remains the
Same the location differs the cost also
varies as it utilizes information from
either the item card or stock keeping
unit if available we will post output
via production Journal JN for these two
lines we are currently not posting any
other consumption or subcontracting
because the item uses standard cost
which will be applied when the item is
added to the inventory change the order
to finish and explore
it navigate to the finished production
order and then to the item Ledger
entries page you'll see two output
transactions with actual costs one from
the item card and one from the stock
keeping Unit Drilling down to Value
entries shows the cost consists of
variance material and capacity the
material cost is identical for both
items since they share the same bill of
material however for stock keeping units
subcontracting costs replace internal
capacity costs accurate and explainable
costing is a key feature of business
Central what can we do better in this
release you can also include
non-inventory cost into the produ C cost
calculation let's see the demo start by
enabling the capability in the
manufacturing setup Page open the cost
shares page from the item card to view
total cost and its components new
columns for rolled up material
non-inventory cost and single level
material non-inventory cost are now
included the non-inventory cost can be
viewed on the statistics page of the
production order next we will proceed
with posting the consumption of
non-inventory items to ensure Clarity
other items and capacities will be
excluded from this example Additionally
the quantity will be increased for
illustrative
purposes change the order to finish and
review
it navigate to the item Ledger entries
page where you can view consumption
entries with non-inventory costs as well
as the cost of finished
items thank you for watching and you can
find more details about these
capabilities in the release noes also
remember to check other videos about
enhancements on Manufacturing